<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list"
			xmlns:t="http://www.openfuxml.org/table"
			xmlns:media="http://www.openfuxml.org/media"
			xmlns:layout="http://www.openfuxml.org/layout"
			id="section.admin.development.er">
	<ofx:title lang="en">Entity Relationship Model</ofx:title>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) is a style sheet language used for describing the look and formatting of a document written in a markup language.
		While most often used to style web pages and user interfaces written in HTML and XHTML,
		the language can be applied to any kind of XML document, including plain XML, SVG and XUL.
		CSS is a cornerstone specification of the web and almost all web pages use CSS style sheets to describe their presentation.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		CSS is designed primarily to enable the separation of document content from document presentation,
		including elements such as the layout, colors, and fonts.
		This separation can improve content accessibility, provide more flexibility and control in the specification of presentation
		characteristics, enable multiple pages to share formatting, and reduce complexity and repetition in the structural content.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<l:list>
	    <l:type ordering="unordered"/>
	    
	    <l:item>
	    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				reset.css: The goal of a reset stylesheet is to reduce browser inconsistencies in things like default line heights, margins and font sizes of headings, and so on.
				The reset styles given here are intentionally very generic.
				There isn't any default color or background set for the body element, for example.
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
		<l:item>
	    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				auPrimeFaces.css
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
	    <l:item>
	    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				aupGeometry.css
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
		<l:item>
	    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				screen.css
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
		<l:item>
	    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				aup.css
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>			
	    
	</l:list>
	
</ofx:section>