<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			 xmlns:media="http://www.openfuxml.org/media"
			 xmlns:table="http://www.openfuxml.org/table"
			 xmlns:layout="http://www.openfuxml.org/layout"
			 xmlns:text="http://www.openfuxml.org/text"
			 xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list"
		id="section.user.ui.interface">
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
        This chapter is essential if you are to understand how to use \product\ as it explains the key components that make up the system.
        This chapter begins by providing an overview of \product, including a quick tour through the screen and the log in.
        Then, we will look at the different navigation types, the symbols used and the wizard. Finally, we will explain how filters are applied and how the status bar works.
        \product\ is largely web-based so you will use it through a \gls{c2}.
        Nevertheless, the use of \product\ is quite different to that of standard web pages. It is a
        <text:emphasis italic="true">\gls{c3}</text:emphasis>, which is an application that is similar to a standard desktop application.
        Therefore, \product\ looks more like <text:emphasis bold="true">Google Mail</text:emphasis> than the web pages of a newspaper.
    </ofx:paragraph>
    <ofx:highlight>
        <ofx:paragraph>
            <ofx:marginalia><ofx:paragraph><text:symbol code="faExclamationTriangle"/></ofx:paragraph></ofx:marginalia>
            Please note that the browser will exchange data with the server because of its web-based nature.
            For example, if you save a project the data of the project will not be stored locally on your computer but sent to the server to be stored in the central database.
            <text:emphasis bold="true">Please avoid <text:emphasis italic="true">Button Mashing</text:emphasis>!</text:emphasis>
            Please do not press a button multiple times while waiting for a system response.
            Hitting the button once will trigger this function. If the system does not respond immediately it is most likely due to network problems.
        </ofx:paragraph>
    </ofx:highlight>

	
</ofx:section>

