<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			 xmlns:media="http://www.openfuxml.org/media"
			 xmlns:table="http://www.openfuxml.org/table"
			 xmlns:layout="http://www.openfuxml.org/layout"
			 xmlns:text="http://www.openfuxml.org/text"
			 xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list"
		id="section.admin.installation.debian">
		
	<ofx:title lang="en">Operating System (Debian Linux)</ofx:title>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
		Debian is an operating system composed of free software mostly carrying the GNU General Public License.
		The operating system is developed by an Internet collaboration of volunteers aligned with The Debian Project.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
		Debian GNU/Linux is one of the most popular Linux distributions for personal computers and network servers.
		Debian is seen as a stable Linux distribution, and as a consequence has been used as a base for other Linux distributions.
		There are over 140 active Debian derivatives, one of the most popular ones is Ubuntu.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
		Since Debian can be used free of charge, it can easily be obtained from the projects website. 
		There is a huge variety of installation methods to choose from.
		A very convenient one is using the minimum installation CD. 
		You can download the disk image for your architecture (mostly i386 for older 32-bit machines 
		and amd64 for newer 64-bit CPUs like Intel Core processors and above) from <text:emphasis style="typewriter">http://www.debian.org/distrib/netinst</text:emphasis>.
		Then the image needs to be written to a CD or DVD recordable.
		The Ubuntu project offers HowTos for all common operating systems like Microsoft Windows, Apple Mac OS X and Linux
		on how to actually burn this image to the disk at <text:emphasis style="typewriter">https://help.ubuntu.com/community/BurningIsoHowto</text:emphasis>.
		Once the CD or DVD is prepared, the computer needs to be booted from the optical disk drive and the (non-graphical) installer
		should be selected from the boot screen.
		The Debian installer then guides you through the complete setup process. 
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:section include="wheezy.xml"/>
	<ofx:section include="jessie.xml"/>
	
	<ofx:section id="section.admin.installation.debian.additional">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Package Manager</ofx:title>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
				Debian comes with a package manager called <text:emphasis style="typewriter">apt-get</text:emphasis>
				that can be used to download and install software automatically.
				The package manager will be used to install several additional packages.
		</ofx:paragraph>
		
	</ofx:section>
	
	<ofx:section include="../tools/nano.xml"/>
	<ofx:section include="../tools/ssh.xml"/>
	<ofx:section include="../tools/less.xml"/>
	<ofx:section include="../tools/unzip.xml"/>

	<ofx:section classifier="ubuntu14">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Sudo</ofx:title>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
			 sudo  is a programme for Unix-like computer operating systems that allows users to run
			 programmes with the security privileges of another user (normally the superuser, or root).
			 Its name is a concatenation of "su" (substitute user) and "do", or take action.
		</ofx:paragraph>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
			Unlike the su command, users typically supply their own password to sudo rather than the
			root password. After authentication, and if the /usr/local/etc/sudoers
			(sometimes found at /etc/sudoers) configuration file permits the user access,
			then the system will invoke the requested command.
			The sudoers configuration file enables a huge amount of configurability, including but not
			limited to: enabling root commands only from the invoking terminal; not requiring a password
			for certain commands; requiring a password per user or group; requiring re-entry of a password
			every time, or never requiring a password at all for a particular command line.
			It can also be configured to permit passing arguments or multiple commands,
			and even supports commands with regular expressions.
			
			As root user you can use the following command to install sudo:
		</ofx:paragraph>
	
		<ofx:listing>
			<ofx:raw>apt-get install sudo</ofx:raw>
		</ofx:listing>
	</ofx:section>
	
	<ofx:section id="section.admin.installation.debian.ubuntu14" classifier="ubuntu14">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Setting the Root Password</ofx:title>
	
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			The next part of the installation is to "set the root password".
			Open the teminal and type in the following command:
			<text:emphasis style="typewriter">sudo passwd root</text:emphasis>
			Double check your password.
		</ofx:paragraph>
	</ofx:section>
</ofx:section>