<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			 xmlns:media="http://www.openfuxml.org/media"
			 xmlns:table="http://www.openfuxml.org/table"
			 xmlns:layout="http://www.openfuxml.org/layout"
			 xmlns:text="http://www.openfuxml.org/text"
			 xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list">
	<ofx:title>Apache Webserver</ofx:title>
				
			<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
				The Apache HTTP Server  is the world's most widely used web server software.
				Originally based on the NCSA HTTPd server, development of Apache began in early 1995 after
				work on the NCSA code stalled. Apache played a key role in the initial growth of the
				World Wide Web, quickly overtaking NCSA HTTPd as the dominant HTTP server,
				and has remained the most popular HTTP server since April 1996.
				In 2009, it became the first web server software to serve more than 100 million websites.
	
				Apache is developed and maintained by an open community of developers
				under the auspices of the Apache Software Foundation.
				Most commonly used on a Unix-like system (usually Linux),
				the software is available for a wide variety of operating systems,
				including Windows, OS X, Linux, Unix, FreeBSD, Solaris, NetWare, OS/2, TPF, OpenVMS and eComStation. Released under the Apache License, Apache is free and open-source software.
	
				As of June 2013, Apache was estimated to serve 54.2% of all active website and 53.3%
				of the top servers across all domains.
			</ofx:paragraph>
		
			<ofx:section container="true" classifier="debian">
				<ofx:title lang="none">Linux Debian: 6 Squeeze and 7 Wheezy)</ofx:title>
	
				<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					Apache can be installed with the command line tool
					<text:emphasis style="typewriter">apt-get</text:emphasis>:
				</ofx:paragraph>
	
			 	<ofx:listing>
					<ofx:raw>apt-get install apache2</ofx:raw>
				</ofx:listing>
				
				<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					Apache can be configured to forward requests to the Application Server. This can be cofigured in
					<text:emphasis style="typewriter">/etc/apache2/sites-available/default</text:emphasis>:
				</ofx:paragraph>
				
				<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/apache/proxy.txt"/>
				
				<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					After configuraiton, the modules <text:emphasis style="typewriter">proxy</text:emphasis>
					and <text:emphasis style="typewriter">proxy_http</text:emphasis>
					need to be activated.
				</ofx:paragraph>
				
				<ofx:listing>
					<ofx:raw>a2enmod proxy proxy_http
service apache2 restart</ofx:raw>
				</ofx:listing>
				
				<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					A automatic forwarding of the user to the application can be configured in 
					<text:emphasis style="typewriter">/var/www/index.html</text:emphasis>:
				</ofx:paragraph>
				
				<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/apache/redirect.html"/>
				
			</ofx:section>


		</ofx:section>